http://www.islamicschool.com.au/about-us/policies/privacy-policy/

Job Vacancies
Professional Learning (PL)
Subjects
English
Health
Humanities and Social Science (HASS)
Islamic Studies
Hifz (Surah Memorisation)
Languages (Arabic)
Quran Reading
Seerah (Life of Prophet Muhammed – pbuh)
School Academic Performance
School Strategic Plan (2015-2020)
Enrolment
Expression of Interest Form (PrePrimary)
Expression of Interest Form (Year 1-6)
News
AllAwardsEventsJob VacanciesProfessional Learning (PL)SubjectsEnglishHealthHumanities and Social Science (HASS)Islamic StudiesHifz (Surah Memorisation)Languages (Arabic)Quran ReadingSeerah (Life of Prophet Muhammed – pbuh)Learning Through InvestigationMathematicsPhysical EducationScienceTechnologiesThe Arts – Visual ArtVideosWalker Learning Approach
Science Week: Deep Blue
The Lock & Key Game
Exploring Natural and Processed Materials
Coronavirus Updates
About Us
About Us
Parent Information Booklet
Curriculum
School Academic Performance
School Strategic Plan (2015-2020)
Job Vacancies
Calendar
Calendar
Al-Hidayah Year Planner
Enrolment
Enrolment
Expression of Interest Form (PrePrimary)
Expression of Interest Form (Year 1-6)
Books and Resources Levy
School Fees
Donation
Contact
Home
About Us
Policies
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Privacy PolicyIntroduction
This Privacy Policy sets out how Al-Hidayah Islamic School (‘the School’) manages personal information provided to or collected by it.
The School is bound by the Australian Privacy Principles (APPs) contained in the Commonwealth Privacy Act 1988 (‘the Privacy Act’).
The School may, from time to time, review and update this Privacy Policy to take account of new laws and technology, changes to the School’s operations and practices and to make sure it remains appropriate to the changing school environment.
Our website address is: http://www.islamicschool.com.au.
What kinds of personal information does the School collect and how does the School collect it?
The type of information the School collects and holds includes (but is not limited to) personal information, including health and other sensitive information, about:
students and parents and/or guardians (‘Parents’) before, during and after the course of a student’s enrolment at the School, including:
name, contact details (including next of kin), date of birth, previous school and religion
Passport and/ or visa details;
Birth certificates;
Immunisation record;
medical information (e.g. details of disability and/or allergies, medical reports and names of doctors);
conduct and complaint records, or other behaviour notes, school, NAPLAN and EasyMark reports;
information about referrals to government welfare agencies;
counselling reports;
any court orders; and
photo and video consent;
job applicants, staff members, volunteers and contractors, including:
name, contact details (including next of kin), date of birth, and religion;
information on job application;
professional development history;
salary and payment information, including superannuation details;
medical information (e.g. details of disability and/or allergies, and medical certificates);
complaint records and investigation reports;
leave details;
work emails and private emails (when using work email address) and Internet browsing history; and
other people who come into contact with the School, including name and contact details and any other information necessary for the particular contact with the School.
Personal Information you provide: The School will generally collect personal information held about an individual by way of forms filled out by Parents, face-to-face meetings and interviews, emails and telephone calls.  On occasions, people other than Parents provide personal information.
Personal Information provided by other people: In some circumstances the School may be provided with personal information about an individual from a third party, for example a report provided by a medical professional or a reference from another school.
Exception in relation to employee records: Under the Privacy Act, the Australian Privacy Principles do not apply to an employee record.  As a result, this Privacy Policy does not apply to the School’s treatment of an employee record, where the treatment is directly related to a current or former employment relationship between the School and employee.
Comments
When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.
An anonymised string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.
Media
If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.
Contact forms
Cookies
If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.
If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.
When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.
If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.
Embedded content from other websites
Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.
These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.
Analytics
How will the School use the personal information you provide?
The School will use personal information it collects from you for the primary purpose of collection, and for such other secondary purposes that are related to the primary purpose of collection and reasonably expected by you, or to which you have consented.
Students and Parents:  In relation to personal information of students and Parents, the School’s primary purpose of collection is to enable the School to provide schooling to students enrolled at the school, exercise its duty of care, and perform necessary associated administrative activities, which will enable students to take part in all the activities of the School.  This includes satisfying the needs of Parents, the needs of the student and the needs of the School throughout the whole period the student is enrolled at the School.
The purposes for which the School uses personal information of students and Parents include:
to keep Parents informed about matters related to their child’s schooling, through correspondence and newsletters;
day-to-day administration of the School;
looking after students’ educational, social and medical wellbeing;
seeking donations and marketing for the School; and
to satisfy the School’s legal obligations and allow the School to discharge its duty of care.
In some cases where the School requests personal information about a student or Parent, if the information requested is not provided, the School may not be able to enrol or continue the enrolment of the student or permit the student to take part in a particular activity.
Job applicants and contractors:  In relation to personal information of job applicants and contractors, the School’s primary purpose of collection is to assess and (if successful) to engage the applicant or contractor, as the case may be.
The purposes for which the School uses personal information of job applicants and contractors include:
administering the individual’s employment or contract, as the case may be;
for insurance purposes;
seeking donations and marketing for the School; and
satisfying the School’s legal obligations, for example, in relation to child protection legislation.
Volunteers: The School also obtains personal information about volunteers who assist the School in its functions or conduct associated activities, such as school events, to enable the School and the volunteers to work together.
Marketing and fundraising:  The School treats marketing and seeking donations for the future growth and development of the School as an important part of ensuring that the School continues to provide a quality learning environment in which both students and staff thrive.  Personal information held by the School may be disclosed to organisations that assist in the School’s fundraising.
Parents, staff, contractors and other members of the wider School community may from time to time receive fundraising information. School publications, like newsletters, which include personal information, may be used for marketing purposes.
Who might the School disclose personal information to and store your information with?
The School may disclose personal information, including sensitive information, held about an individual for educational, administrative and support purposes. This may include to:
other schools and teachers at those schools;
government departments;
medical practitioners;
people providing educational, support and health services to the School, including specialist visiting teachers, volunteers, counsellors and providers of learning and assessment tools;
assessment and educational authorities, including the Australian Curriculum, Assessment and Reporting Authority and AISWA;
people providing administrative and financial services to the School;
recipients of School publications, such as newsletters;
students’ parents or guardians;
anyone you authorise the School to disclose information to; and
anyone to whom we are required or authorised to disclose the information to by law, including child protection laws.
The School may use online or ‘cloud’ service providers to store personal information and to provide services to the School that involve the use of personal information, such as services relating to email, instant messaging and education and assessment applications.  Some limited personal information may also be provided to these service providers to enable them to authenticate users that access their services.  This personal information may be stored in the ‘cloud’ which means that it may reside on a cloud service provider’s servers which may be situated outside Australia.
An example of such a cloud service provider is Google. Google provides the ‘Google Apps for Education’ (GAFE) including Gmail, and stores and processes limited personal information for this purpose.  School personnel and the AIS and its service providers may have the ability to access, monitor, use or disclose emails, communications (e.g. instant messaging), documents and associated administrative data for the purposes of administering GAFE and ensuring its proper use.
How does the School treat sensitive information?
In referring to ‘sensitive information’, the School means: information relating to a person’s racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religion, trade union or other professional or trade association membership, philosophical beliefs, sexual orientation or practices or criminal record, that is also personal information; health information and biometric information about an individual.
Sensitive information will be used and disclosed only for the purpose for which it was provided or a directly related secondary purpose, unless you agree otherwise, or the use or disclosure of the sensitive information is allowed by law.
Management and security of personal information
The School’s staff are required to respect the confidentiality of students’ and Parents’ personal information and the privacy of individuals.
The School has in place steps to protect the personal information the School holds from misuse, interference and loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure by use of various methods including locked storage of paper records and password access rights to computerised records.
Access and correction of personal information
Under the Commonwealth Privacy Act, an individual has the right to seek and obtain access to any personal information which the School holds about them and to advise the School of any perceived inaccuracy.  Students will generally be able to access and update their personal information through their Parents, but older students may seek access and correction themselves.
There are some exceptions to these rights set out in the applicable legislation.
To make a request to access or to update any personal information the School holds about you or your child, please contact the School Office in person, by telephone or in writing.  The School may require you to verify your identity and specify what information you require.  The School may charge a fee to cover the cost of verifying your application and locating, retrieving, reviewing and copying any material requested.  If the information sought is extensive, the School will advise the likely cost in advance. If we cannot provide you with access to that information, we will provide you with written notice explaining the reasons for refusal.
Consent and rights of access to the personal information of students
The School respects every Parent’s right to make decisions concerning their child’s education.
Generally, the School will refer any requests for consent and notices in relation to the personal information of a student to the student’s Parents.  The School will treat consent given by Parents as consent given on behalf of the student, and notice to Parents will act as notice given to the student.
Parents may seek access to personal information held by the School about them or their child by contacting the School Office in person, by telephone or in writing.  However, there may be occasions when access is denied.  Such occasions would include where release of the information would have an unreasonable impact on the privacy of others, or where the release may result in a breach of the School’s duty of care to the student.
The School may, at its discretion, on the request of a student grant that student access to information held by the School about them, or allow a student to give or withhold consent to the use of their personal information, independently of their Parents.  This would normally be done only when the maturity of the student and/or the student’s personal circumstances warrant it.
How long we retain your data
If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognise and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.
For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.
What rights you have over your data
If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.
Where we send your data
Visitor comments on the school website may be checked through an automated spam detection service.
Enquiries and complaints
If you would like further information about the way the School manages the personal information it holds, or wish to complain that you believe that the School has breached the Australian Privacy Principles please contact the School Principal by writing or telephone (08) 9351 8593.  The School will investigate any complaint and will notify you of the making of a decision in relation to your complaint as soon as is practicable after it has been made.
Additional information
How we protect your data
What data breach procedures we have in place
What third parties we receive data from
What automated decision making and/or profiling we do with user data
Industry regulatory disclosure requirements
Site MapSign In
Office 365
SEQTA
Seesaw
AISWA
News
AllAwardsEventsJob VacanciesProfessional Learning (PL)SubjectsEnglishHealthHumanities and Social Science (HASS)Islamic StudiesHifz (Surah Memorisation)Languages (Arabic)Quran ReadingSeerah (Life of Prophet Muhammed – pbuh)Learning Through InvestigationMathematicsPhysical EducationScienceTechnologiesThe Arts – Visual ArtVideosWalker Learning Approach
Science Week: Deep Blue
The Lock & Key Game
Exploring Natural and Processed Materials
Coronavirus Updates
About Us
About Us
Parent Information Booklet
Curriculum
School Academic Performance
School Strategic Plan (2015-2020)
Job Vacancies
Calendar
Calendar
Al-Hidayah Year Planner
Enrolment
Enrolment
Expression of Interest Form (PrePrimary)
Expression of Interest Form (Year 1-6)
Books and Resources Levy
School Fees
Donation
Contact
EDITOR PICKS
Coronavirus Updates
April 22, 2020
Supersonic Science
August 29, 2019
Ramadan Food Donation
June 8, 2018
POPULAR POSTS
Welcome to Al-Hidayah Islamic School – 2019
January 31, 2019
Ayman, Year 3, has memorised Juz 29 of the Qur’an Kareem,...
June 1, 2018
Zakat for Kids
August 17, 2018
POPULAR CATEGORYEvents31Learning Through Investigation27Videos21Health19Science17Islamic Studies13Humanities and Social Science (HASS)12Walker Learning Approach11Professional Learning (PL)10
ABOUT USAl-Hidayah Islamic School provides high quality Islamic Studies and Government Curriculum in a friendly Islamic environment.
Tel: +618 9351 8593Contact us: info@islamicschool.com.auFOLLOW US
Disclaimer
Privacy
Contact Us
© 2018 Al-Hidayah Islamic School (ABN 72 481 406 449)
